Erin Halden

FULL SCACK SOFCWARE engineer

San Bruno, CA • (415) 823-4794
erinhalden@erininabox.com
linkedin.com/in/erininabox
github.com/erininabox
erininabox.com

about me

I am a full-stack software engineer who believes in using clean code to create ethical, accessible products. With 10 years experience in public mental health and education, I bring to the table a passion for making information accessible, and cultivating exceptional teams that focus on creative problem-solving, with an eye toward the bigger picture.

Front End | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Materialize, Flexbox, Grid, WordPress

Back End | Node.js, Express.js, PHP, RESTful API, MongoDB, Flask, SQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Python, Mongoose, JSON

TOOLS & MCGHODOLOGICS | MVC, SPA architecture, Command Line Interface, Responsive Web Design, Version control (Git/Github), VSCode, Heroku, Slack, Trello, Linux

SOFC SKILLS | Crisis management, team building, communication, creative problem solving,

EDUCATION

7/2021—9/2021 | Software Engineering Immersive General Assembly, San Francisco , CA

12/2010 | MA Linguistics
California State University, Northridge, CA

6/2004 | BA Natural Sciences Evergreen State College , Olympia, WA

EXPERIENCE

10/2019—5/2021 | Case Manager PRC Baker Places, San Francisco, CA

8/2016—10/2019 | Residential Treatment Counselor Progress Foundation, San Francisco, CA

8/2014—12/2014 | Middle School English Teacher SFUSD, San Francisco, CA

7/2013—8/2014 | High School English Teacher CAVA, Los Angeles, CA

11/2012-4/2013 | Middle School Intervention Specialist MUSD, Moorpark, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

BOOKWA'D | Book management app for K-12 libraries 9/2021 MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Mongoose

- * Independently designed a book management app for K-12 educators to more easily manage large book sets
- * Implemented a multi-schema database using MongoDB and Mongoose with a many-to-many schema design
- Created a mobile-first responsive user experience built on top of a modularized MERN app with full CRUD capability

WâYFârêr | Client-directed travel app 8/2021 CSS (Flexbox & Grid), Bootstrap, MERN stack: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js

- * Designed and implemented a travel blog web app according to specifications and wireframes provided by a client in a team of five people, and engaged in version control by leveraging Github's branching and forking
- * Used MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js to create a fully modular app that employs a one-to-many data model
- * Coached team members in use of CSS Flexbox and CSS Grid
- * Collaborated with teammate to pair program the RESTful routes and to implement full CRUD capability

ENGAYGED | Responsive wedding-planning web app 8/2021 JavaScript, Express.js, EJS, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap

- * Mobile-responsive, modular web app built in a team of two during a one-week sprint following MVC and REST Routing protocols with any eye for scalability, user experience, and future modifiability
- * Server-rendered web app uses Express.js and EJS in conjunction with MongoDB to deliver full CRUD functionality
- * Practiced pair programming and version management with Github in order to effectively collaborate to create high-quality code from inception to delivery

GIGA-CAL | Responsive browser game JavaScript, HTML, CSS (Flexbox & Grid)

Responsive browser game using JavaScript, CSS3, Flexbox, and Grid to create an accessible and fun user experience

7/2021